Guide to the John B. Duncan papers, 1932-1989 MS2055
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Reference files, 1954-1989; MS2055 Series 5; 2 Linear feet
  - Reference Files, Minority Integration into Boards in DC, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Reference Files, N.AAC.P., Report and Program for Dinner, 1950 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Reference Files, National Capital Downtown Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Reference Files, National Capital Downtown Committee, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Reference Files, National Capital Downtown Committee, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Reference Files, Neighborhood Commons, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Reference Files, Negro Solidarity, paper byJohn Duncan, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Reference Files, President's Council on Pennsylvania Avenue, Release and Synopsis, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Reference Files, President's Council on Pennsylvania Avenue, Report, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Reference Files, President's Council on Pennsylvania Avenue, Correspondence, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Roger W. Jones, 1959 April 28 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, James Dumpson, 1960-1962 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Made at St. Elizabeth's Hospital, 1961-1963 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Unknown speaker at Howard University, 1961 March 07 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, S.E. Duncan, 1961 June 28 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, William B. Tollen, 1962 March 02 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Ralph Bunche, 1962 May 07 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Joseph Mitchell, 1962 September 12 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Sidney Spector, 1962 October 22 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Eulogy for Eleanor Roosevelt by Ambassador Adlai E. Stevenson, 1962 November 17 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, B.M. McKelway, 1962 December 10 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Robert Wagner, 1962 December (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Lester Velie, 1963 January (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1963 January 06 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, John S. Hayes, 1963 January 12 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Robert C. Weaver, 1963 March 28 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Walter Tobriner, 1963 April 02 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Roy Wilkins, 1963 April 29 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, B.T. McGraw, 1963 May 04 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1963-1967 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1963 May 30 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1963 June 09 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, John S. Hayes, 1963 September 26 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Harle Selassie, 1963 October 02 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Hubert H. Humphrey, 1963 November 21 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Albert Mindlin, 1963 December (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Benjamin McKelway, 1964 January 10 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, John Hayes, 1964 February 05 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Alan Bible, 1964 February 07 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Robert Weaver, 1964 March 18 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, John D. Rockefeller 3RD, 1964 April 12 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Robert Weaver, 1964 April 20 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Bennetta Washington, 1964 May 01 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Jennings Randolph, 1964 August 02 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Eulogy of John F. Kennedy by Wallace Sabinus Lewis, 1964 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, John Hoffman, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Schuyler Lowe, Circa 1965 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Whitney Young, 1965 January 26 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Roy Wilkins, 1965 January 26 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Lewellyn Jennings, 1965 May 22 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Lyndon B. Johnson, 1965 June 04 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Sterling Brown, 1965 November 14 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, A. Philip Randolph, 1966 September 04 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Joseph D. Tydings, 1966 May 25 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Robert Weaver, 1966 August 01 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Victor R. Daly, 1967 February 09 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Assistant Secretary, Board of Commissioners, 1967 July 19 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Patrick Cardinal O'Boyle, 1967 July 28 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, William Van Dyke, 1967 September 14 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Dore Schary, 1967 September (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Robert Weaver, 1967 November 20 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Donald Carruth, 1968 April 05 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Edward L.R. Elson, 1968 June 10 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Dr. Jackson, undated (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, F.E. Ropshaw, undated (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, F.E. Ropshaw, undated (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Barbara Dill, undated (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Reference Files, Speeches, Fred Hetzel, undated (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Reference Files, Telephone Directory for US Senate and House, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Reference Files, Telephone Directory for DC Government, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Reference Files, Telephone Directory for Department of the Interior, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Reference Files, Telephone Directory for region from the Metropolitan Washington Council of Governments, 1968 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Reference Files, USO survey, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Reference Files, Washington Urban League, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Reference Files, White House Press Releases, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Reference Files, Work Release Plan, undated (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - Reference Files, Youth Opportunity Campaign, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - 40A Travel Authorization Files, Department of Interior, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 46)
- Personal files, 1951-1989; MS2055 Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains biographical sheets, correspondence, medical records, civil service application, Duncan's book about the card game Bridge "New Dimension Bidding in Contract Bridge" and the eulogy delivered by his sister at his funeral. The material is dated from 1951-89. The biographical sheets for Duncan are from 1951, 1960, and 1971. The personal correspondence to and from friends and family dates from 1960-61 and 1967-68.
  - Personal Files, Biographical Sheets, 1951-1971 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Personal Files, Medical Records & Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Personal Files, Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Personal Files, Solicitations for contributions from Various Causes, 1960-1961 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Personal Files, Correspondence to Doris Johnson, friend of the Duncans, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Personal Files, Correspondence, Congratulations for appointment of Special Assistant to the Secretary of the Interior, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Personal Files, Correspondence, Commendations and Recommendations for people, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Personal Files, Correspondence, 1967-1968 August (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Personal Files, Correspondence, 1968 September-November (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Personal Files, Executive Inventory Record under the Executive Assignment System, 1967 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Personal Files, To-Do list and College Schedule for Joan Duncan (daughter), 1968-1969 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Personal Files, Book by John Duncan, New Dimension Bidding in Contract Bridge, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Personal Files, "New Dimension Bidding Guide For Certified Teachers" byJohn B. Duncan, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Personal Files, Correspondence and Eulogy of Duncan's sister, Elizabeth Duncan Koontz, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Script of book, undated (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, newsletters, photographs, clippings, 1927, 1967-1987; Series 6 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Scrapbooks, 1932-1989; MS2055 Series 7; 8 Linear feet
  This collection contains scrapbooks dated from 1932-89. These scrapbooks not only document his business and personal activities, but they also record significant events that occured in the District of Columbia and within the federal government. The scrapbooks contain clippings, invitations, speeches, greeting cards, and programs. The scrapbooks are full of personal memorabilia such as the 1927 issue of "The Pricean," his high school paper, which featured articles written by Duncan and honors he had received. The scrapbooks also have articles featuring Duncan's mother, who was named "Ideal Mother" by "Afro Magazine" in 1949. A significant amount of information on Duncan's sister, Elizabeth Koontz, director of the Women's Bureau of the U.S. Department of Labor and U.S. delegate to the U.N. Commission on the Status of Women in the 1960s and 1970s. Unfortunate events are also recorded in the scrapbooks, including clippings and programs regarding the death of Duncan's first wife, Edith, in 1966 and the 1968 death of his brother, Samuel, president of Livingstone College for ten years.
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1950 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1950 October-1954 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1954-1962 May (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1963 April (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1963 May-December (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1964 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1964 July-1965 July (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1964 July-1966 May (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1967 November-1968 November (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1969-1971 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1971 July-1974 January (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1974 January-1975 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1975 December-1983 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1977 January-1982 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1984-1987 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1987-1989 (Box 40, Folder 2)
- Clippings, 1960-1967; MS2055 Series 8; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains clippings and articles from numerous magazines. The material dates from 1960-67. Periodicals in the series includes: "The Capitol Spotlight," "The Evening Star," "The Washington Afro-American," "The Washington Post," and "The Washington Tribune." There are other miscellaneous publications.
  - Clippings, The Capitol Spotlight, 1961-1964 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, The Evening Star, 1962-1967 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, The Negro History Bulletin, 1961 October (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, The Washington Afro-American, 1961-1965 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, The Washington Post, 1961 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, The Washington Post, 1962-1963 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Clippings, The Washington Post, 1964-1967 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Clippings, The Washington Tribune, 1964 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1961-1965 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, Miscellaneous, 1960-1963 (Box 41, Folder 10)
- Memorabilia, undated; MS2055 Series 9; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains a high school athletic letter, most likely a gift from a school he visited; two ashtrays, one of which was given to Duncan by the President's Committee on the Employment of the Handicapped and the other unidentified; and a memo pad from the desk of Commissioner Duncan.
  - Memorabilia, High School Letter in the shape of a "B", with "JHS" along side, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia, Ashtray, from The President's Committee on Employment of the Handicapped, undated (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Memorabilia, Ashtray, wood appearance with a place for cigarettes with a lid with a mill and stream scene on it and a small ash container next to it, undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Memorabilia, Memo Pad from Commissioner Duncan's desk, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)